all right my
friends
um I have to drink to make this video a
little bit and that's because I don't
like saying what I'm about to
say you should get a red hat certified
engineer certificate if you want to work
in
operations if you want to work in
operations high performance Computing
devops infastructure engineering
security if any of those things interest
you you really should could pursue a red
hat certified engineering Dee why am I
drinking because I hate saying that I
absolutely hate it I hate it I sold my
stock in red hat that I held in 2020 or
something like 2002 or something because
they sold out the
pedora there's been I mean there's been
so many things about about red hat that
I do not approve of that I do not
like but this video is for you this
video is not
about um to drink more beer it's just
recording it's just re-recording just an
excuse to drink more beer am I slurring
my words
yet I am Desperately Seeking Balmer Peak
uh to finish this
video
and this video is very short so like
it's G to be under five minutes and the
message is very
simple get your red hat certified
engineer
certificate just do it pay the money
figure it out make it happen here's why
getting a red hat certified engineer
certificate is more valuable than a
computer science degree in terms of
getting most jobs particularly jobs in
in infrastructure
engineering so I'm not I'm not talking
about computer science there are people
that will give you a job for having a
computer science degree think about how
much money I computer science degree
costs how much money does a certified
engineer in Red Hat
cost probably about 130th of the money I
have no idea I haven't even looked I do
not have my redhead certified engineer
but I'm going to tell you right now even
though I'm 56 years old I'm going to
retire in six years I am still going to
pursue the Knowledge and Skills
necessary to be a redhead certified
engineer I I worded that very carefully
I may not actually
pay to become a redhead certified
engineer but I very seriously plan on
acquiring the skills necessary to become
a certified engineer why because my
immediate job responsibilities include
leveraging Red Hats version and of
anible in the Enterprise in order to
deploy for example my kubernetes login
code that I wrote so that the entire
Enterprise can log into kubernetes and
do whatever they want want this is all
stuff that I am regularly paid a very
handsome salary for and my pursuit of
the red hat certified
engineer is in line with that
particularly because there are certain
things which you cannot learn any other
way it's not like I can fire up a lab
with running redot anible configuration
manager right I just can't do it the
unfortunate reality of propriety AR
software such as this such as red had is
that there's really no way for you to
learn it this this was true for db2 by
the way with IBM it's a database
platform that people would spend
thousands of dollars to learn because
there was no way to learn it on your
own seriously people would spend
thousands of dollars to learn db2 on
their own and then they would become the
industry experts in db2 and they would
basically tell people what to do because
they're they would they would they were
making six seven six figure salaries you
know in the ' 80s because there was no
way to be a db2 engineer without having
invested a serious amount of money to
even understand how it
works the same is not true of redhead
Enterprise
but it's partially true so therefore I
think you I think you should consider it
um and that that is where you should go
about doing that
um it makes me very sad to recommend
learning a certification and paying the
money and I mean serious where's my
beer I don't like what is I report on
what is you know why because I'm here
for you and I said this before I'm going
to say it
again I am here to help you I am here to
help you make money and then I'm going
to end the video on this then you can do
what you want outside of that and I I
tried to make a version of this video
before I'm going to try to make it more
simply Chris NOA the late great Chris
NOA said we learn go most of us will be
programming go for the rest of our lives
but rust represents a new hope for a
better
future and she proceeded to then code in
Rust until she
died and the sentiment is valuable
whether you're it's related to go
programming or it's related to accepting
what is versus what you want for the
future you can compartmentalize those
two and it's okay it's okay you don't
have to be you know you don't have to
consider you're not you're not you're
not you know SE selling sexual favors
you're just selling red
hat in order to pay the
bills okay and then you know and then at
the same time I mean this is kind of I I
really mean that I actually knew
somebody somebody some people may know
this my ex my my son-in-law dated a
dated a sex worker and she was also a um
strange absolutely strange story she was
also a social worker by day she was a
social worker by night she was a sex
worker and I always thought that was so
interesting because she paid the bills
with her sex work but she you know she
was salt to the Earth um uh you know
making
nothing do you need to sell your body no
you need to do you need to sell yourself
on a red hat probably and and I plan to
do the same I I'm going to pursue
redhead certified engineer whether or
not I get the certificate or not uh I
want you to know and I am definitely
slurring my speech because making a
video like this makes me very sad I
don't like the way the world is
currently I do not like that you have to
pay you have to bow down to the temple
of red hat even though red hat made all
their money off of Open Source and all
the contributions from all the
hardworking individual Linux
contributors the world has ever known
for free and they turned around and
capitalized on all that and made [__]
Bank off of it my one swear
word does that make me sick to my
stomach yes absolutely does it mean it's
not the truth no so accepting what is
and capitalizing on what is in order to
live live another day and make something
better of our world is essential it's
essential it's a theme and Mr Robot as
well I'm going to end the video there
bye-bye